Chun-Yu, Chen (Aloha)

No. 125-5 Ren en, Gongguan Township , Miaoli County 363, Taiwan (R.O.C.) Email: y.alohac@gmail.com Phone: +886 937206415

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alohacc

Github: https://github.com/alChaCC

Blog: http://ccaloha.cc

Lead Ruby on Rails Development Engineer

Full Stack Enterprise Web Development - Agile/Dev Ops Development Practice

Over 5 years qualified working experience in software development, included 3 years in Ruby on Rails development especially in E-commerce and content-based websites and 3 years in system integration testing. Participated more than 10+ projects as main developer included data analytics, global api and a open source project. I'm self-motivated and have a passionate mind. Plus, I'm really good at learning and solving problem. I'm looking for a challenging role that utilizes my previous skills and experiences especially in Data Analytics and Web/Application development.

Technical Skill Set

Programming Language	Databases	Open API / 3rd Party	Other Technologies
• Ruby / Ruby on Rails	• MySQL	Google Analytcis	• CSS
• Java Scripts	• MongoDB	 Google Tag Management 	• Git
• R		• Facebook API / Ads	• Ubuntu
 Python / C / C++ 		• AWS	• D3.js

Professional Experience

i-true Communications inc Lead Ruby on Rails developer

2014 - Present

It was my responsibility to help ITs and operators solving their critical problems and to study new technology for our company next-generation products then make it happen.

- As a lead developer, I design and implement most of our core products such as a largest cosmetic and beauty product community website in Taiwan (70% core codes are written by me included administrator panel, authorization, email tracking, product weekly rankings, effectiveness Of marketing campaigns...etc) and a data manage platform for AD retargeting.
- As a researcher, I have to learn new technology and share with not only IT but also other employees. For example, I open a 6 months class for google analytics in weekly company meeting. Plus, I'm working with data at scale with MongoDB and building up a behaviors tracking system and administrator panel system. And I use map reduce and aggregation for accelerating pageviews extraction and audience classification.
- **As a data scientist**, I use R and D3.js for reviews data analytics and using text segmentation, scikit-learn to build up a BI system for finding the relationship between keywords and cosmetic products, which will be used in recommendation system and data management platform.
- * As a systems engineer, By using AWS, I set up a Ruby on Rails production and staging environment in Ubuntu server. Also, I use Route53 for domain routing, S3 for assets uploading, RDS for our MySQL database, ELB for distributing workloads and EC2 for search engine and schedule jobs.

Freelancer 2013 – present

Full Stack Web Developer

To understand client's needs and quickly and correctly provide a Web application solution.

* As a developer, I build up a fashion and beauty E-commerce website included Google Analytics Enhanced Ecommerce Tracking, On/off the shelf scheduly, Discount feature, CRM feature, Coupon,

Search engine using Sunspot, Payment with credit card or ATM, Email ...etc. Plus, I work with clients building a ERP system especially for fashion and beauty industry.

- As a systems engineer, I set up and maintain a Ruby on Rails production environment in Ubuntu server and use Monit to monitor systems.
- As a volunteer and consultant, I architect and implement a crowdfunding website for Green Dot Communities, a company that installs free rooftop solar panels for old age homes

i-TRUE Commerce inc Ruby on Rails developer

2014/01 - 2014/07

Working in a 4 people start up company, my obligation is to maintain and development the online box subscription website and support everything.

- As a only one developer, I maintain and develop an easy CRM analytics system for increasing sales by finding who has higher possibility to subscribe box. And I introduce Google Tag Management into our website.
- As a supporter, I almost participate all strategic marketing meetings and develop application to support marketing idea. This included using Facebook API to find out who send message in our fan page and give him a gift and building a javascript game: winwheel that user can use reward point to play and get a gift.

ITRI Cloud Computing Center for Mobile Application

2010 - 2013

Software Engineer

My responsibility is to conduct software testing, test automation and support building TaaS for continuous integration.

- As a Quality Assurance Engineer, I mainly responsible for storage testing included Data Main Storage. Data Second Storage and Wide Area Data Backup.
- As a Software Engineer, I build up a automated testing using Robotframework, Selenium, shell script and Python) and integrate Jenkins, SpiraTest and Jira for continuous integration.

Education and Training

Education:

2004-2008 2008-2010 National United University: Bachelor of Science, Electrical and Electronics Engineering National Taiwan University: Master of Science. Biomedical Electronics and Bioinformatics

• In order to predict optical parameters such as the scattering coefficient, oxygen saturation and hemoglobin concentration, I used 2 models - the forward model and the inverse model. I implemented the Monte Carlo scaling method by using C++ as forward method. The inverse model used the Levenerg-Marquardt least square method to fit our simulated spectrum. For streamline the research, I built a convenient graphic user interface integrated with Matlab and C++

Technical Courses Completed:

2015 DSP Data Analysis - Advanced, Data Analysis - Basic 2013-2015 Code School JavaScript Road Trip Part 1, Assembling Sass, Ruby Bits Part 2 Ruby Bits, Try R, Try Git, Testing with RSpec, Real-time Web with Node.js, Journey Into Mobile, Rails Testing for Zombies, Rails for Zombies 2, Rails Best Practices, Rails for Zombies, Anatomy of Backbone.js, Surviving APIs with Rails, CoffeeScript, jQuery Air: Captain's Log, jQuery Air: First Flight, **CSS Cross-Country** 2009/12 National Taiwan University Data structure & Advanced C++ programming 2008/9 National Taiwan University C/C++ programing

Other

Patent 張庭嘉, 陳俊宇, 吳延文, "行動裝置及利用行動裝置執行互動遊戲之方法 PORTABLE APPARATUS AND

METHOD FOR PLAYING INTERACTIVE GAMES BY PORTABLE APPARATUS" Taiwan. I488052.

filed June 11, 2015.

Certifications Google Analytics - Google, June 2015 to December 2016